

# **Sukhomoy Bhattacharya**

3/21, CIT Buildings, Christopher Road, Kolkata, India +91 98749 42043 sukhomoy.bhattacharya@hotmail.com linkedin.com/sukhomoybhattacharya/ Skype: sukhomoy.bhattacharya\_1

Domain Agnostic techno-functional professional with 19 years of experience in Information technology, including 15 years in Data and BI Management. More than 4 years of experience with Power BI and Web BI. Client management exposure with a medium band (8-10) team leadership experience. Love helping business leaders make sense of data to make easy decisions on it. Along with business acumen and communication skills, have a strong 5 years of technical background to work well with technical teams. Expert in SQL Server, Power BI, Advanced Excel with VBA Macro. Always keen to share knowledge and experience to enable and empower others. Wants to help shape the strategy for business intelligence in a fast-paced and growing organization.

#### Skills

- Management Information (MIS)\*
- Business Intelligence (BI)
- Data Management\*
- Data Analytics\*
- Data Visualization\*
- BI Team Management\*

- Microsoft BI (SSIS, SSAS, SSRS)
- SQL Server\*, Teradata, Oracle, MS Access
- Office 365 with Advance Excel & VBA Macro\*
- Power BI\*(+DAX,+M), OBIEE
- Python including NumPy, Pandas, Matplotlib
- \* Considered as an expert

# Work Experience

06/2020 - CURRENT

## **Business Intelligence Manager / Straits Bridge Analytics, India**

Lead a highly visible solution-oriented business intelligence product. Align the product design as per internal and external consumer surveys. Responsible for continuous enhancement of the product. Support BI Tools and vendor validation, collateral management, and document management. Manage development strategies and policies. Implement business Intelligence 'best practices'. Optimize qualitative and quantitative delivery of the product in an agile process.

Successfully delivered phase 1 of the product (BanklQ).

05/2017 - 06/2020

## Business Intelligence Manager / Straits Bridge Advisors, Dubai

Primarily Set up and manage the team including hiring, training to support the BOT (Build, Operate and Transfer) model. Transform business requirements to technological scopes, manage documentation, and Data Strategy. Manage and Enhance data analytics scopes and BI systems, Ensure proper data quality across users' teams and stakeholders. Manage testing protocols and procedures, Work with Business analysts and Business partners, Manage Data Engineering, and ETL. Manage data visualizations and BAU Reports and ensuring of Business Intelligence 'best practices' along with data security.

Successfully completed a project with a renowned bank in KSA. Recently done an enterprise diagnosis project for a growing bank in Oman to highlight required BI implementation to integrate BI operations all over the bank.

09/2014 - 11/2016

# Marketing Analyst / Citruss TV, Dubai

Plan and organize promotional events, interpret business needs into data and analyse data to recommend business action, Develop and implement merchandising plans, assist in building and managing offer budgets, Manage relationships with partners and vendors.

Increased 7% revenue by customer retention analysis and customer target and saved 5% delivery and handling cost on Customer Segmentation Analysis. Established Campaign process automation and tracking dashboard.

12/2011-09/2014

# Marketing Analyst / Standard Chartered Bank, Dubai

Interpret business needs into data. Improve leads generation process by automation. Provide valuable insights to improve and maintain a high-quality data dictionary. Develop advanced, self-service reporting and data visualization capabilities and interactive dashboards supporting key business imperatives and initiatives. Monitor and analyse variances and performance trends within channels. Responsible for tracking routine and ad hoc reports on all acquisition, retention, cross-sell, upsell campaigns to achieve goals.

Saved 10% Resource Cost on Leads Generation Process with Automation. Implemented an Automated Campaign Tracking System that increased 2% overall revenue. Awarded with Best Campaign Award in 2013.

# Business Analyst / Emirates Islamic Bank, Dubai

Generate weekly, monthly, and quarterly reporting for all major metrics, goals tracking, revenue tracking, and other paid search initiatives. Develop and present standard and ad-hoc reports and analyses to stakeholders across the organization. Work closely with Business Intelligence, to ensure timely and accurate maintenance of internal dashboards and data management. Perform analyses to ensure data integrity. Build BI dashboards prototype to analyse and uncover data patterns that result in recommendations for business improvement. Communicate insights and suggest improvements based on data and observed trends.

Implemented hierarchical sales performance MIS model, that increased 3.5% overall yearly revenue. In addition, implemented customer 360 Datamart.

04/2007 -06/2009

#### **Business Intelligence Consultant / Emirates Bank International, Dubai**

Responsible for enabling and running data migrations across different databases and different servers. Defines and implements data stores based on system requirements and consumer requirements. Performing thorough testing and validation to support the accuracy of data transformations and data verification. Ensure proper data governance and quality across analytics team and the business users. Play an analytical role to perform ad-hoc analysis of data stored in the business' databases and writes SQL scripts, stored procedures, functions, and views to streamline these analytical functions. Highlight insights by applying descriptive analytics across a variety of business domains.

Save 2%, Resource cost on Automation for data transformation, cleansing and data report preparations.

11/2006 - 04/2007

# Senior Software Consultant / GTL Ltd, Mumbai

Adhere and track development Documents, security, and best practices. Support Business and MIS Team for their On-Line Analysis. Understand Business Requirement or Change Request and Functional Specification, Preparing technical Specification and DFD. Developing software logic, Unit testing. Designing Front-end VBA based forms. Create Database Objects (Including Views, Store Procedures, Functions, Triggers and SQL Schedule Jobs). Implemented bulk data Transformation process between SQL Server and Excel through VBA and SQL Programming.

10/2005 -11/2006

# Senior Software Consultant / Sai Freight Ltd., Mumbai

Review and analysis legacy errors and gaps. Review Modern Business Requirement and Functional Specification. Prepare DFD, PFD, And Technical Specification. Develop software business logic, scopes, and rules, and constraints. Develop and design a Database architecture and reporting model. Create Database Objects (including Views, Store Procedures, Functions, and Triggers). Manage off-site Resources. Track the project timeline. Designing Front-end windows-based forms. Integration Testing, UAT Support and End User Training. Work on a dead project and made it live and completed beyond timeline that saved 60 Man-days.

11/2004 - 10/2005

#### Software Consultant / NPower, New Castle Upon Tyne

Worked in a development team as a team member for Northern Enhancement Project. Understand BRD & CRD, Prepare & Review Program Specification, Prepare & Review Test Case Specification, Prepare & Review Code and Unit testing.

02/2002 - 08/2004

## Software Developer / Techno-Fin Solution, Calcutta

Understand Business Requirement and Preparing System Specification, Designing Front-end and software logic, Create Database Objects (Tables, Views, Store Procedures, Functions, and Triggers), Perform required testing.

## **Education**

12/1996

**Bachelor of Science / Calcutta University, Calcutta** 

### **Activities**

08/2019

Data Science for Manager Certification / Data Camp (Online)

01/2017

Dashboards and Data Discovery Certification / Micro Strategy, Mumbai

09/2010

**Project Management Certification / Cambridge Educational Institute, Dubai** 

## References

Harish Kumar
Director
StraitsBridge Advisors
+91 82811 56088
harish.kumar@straitsbridge.com

Melvin Mathews
Vice President - Product, Proposition & Portfolio
Mashreq Bank
+971 50 8517270
melvinis@gmail.com